Akitha Medagoda

94A Walmsley Road, Favona, Auckland, NZ • +64 21 280 1232 • akithamedagoda@gmail.com https://akitha02.github.io/portfolio/

OBJECTIVE

I'm a final year Mechanical Engineering student with knowledge and experience from numerous engineering projects. I'm well trained in principles of mechanical engineering like AutoCAD (Autodesk inventor) and CAE (ANSYS). Highly organized, analytical and detail oriented with excellent communication skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mechanical Engineering Intern

Nov 2022 - Mar 2023

Rinnai NZ - Mangere, AUK

- Helped create a cutting-edge hot water cylinder with environment heat recovery system.
- Researched about causes and solution for unexpected warranty returns.
- Numerically analyzed effects of insulation using CAE software such as ANSYS and SolidWorks Heat transfer simulation.
- Designed and created a mold using sheet metal for insulation K value testing.
- Assisted senior engineers.

Mechanical Assistant

Mar 2022 - June 2022

Cable-Ways - Avondale, AUK

- Mechanical assembler.
- Construct server and battery cabinets from scratch.
- Operate drill press and sheet metal shear machine.
- Operating pneumatic rivet and nutsert gun.
- Maintain utmost discretion when dealing with sensitive topics.

Fabrication Welder

Nov 2021 - Jan 2021

CMP controls. - Mangere, AK

- This role was to help produce electrical Transformers of varies sizes and specifications
- Operating Auto welding machine.
- Manual TIG welding non machinable parts and fixing errors caused by the auto welder.

Volunteer

Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

Auckland grammar school - Newmarket, AUK

- Volunteered with groups and organizations to help make measurable differences for program recipients.
- Collected donations for causes such as Cystic fibrosis, Auckland city mission. Environmental cleanup, mainly around Mount Eden.

Production Worker

Eden Office - Mangere, AUK

- Jul 2021 Jul 2021
- Supported machine operators in setup and operation of production equipment resulting in efficient runs.
- Conducted performance tests and quality assurance tests of goods to meet product certification requirements.
- Manufactured office furniture using electric and air compressed tools. About 250 chairs per day.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

2020 - 2023

The University of Auckland - Auckland city, AUK

- Member of Motorsport Club
- Member of Mechanical and Mechatronic student association

Highschool diploma

2015 - 2019

Auckland Grammar school - Newmarket, AUK Member of Cycling squad, Interact club, Cricket, orienteering

SKILLS

- TIG welding
- Fluent in Autodesk inventor and in ANSYS
- Web and tech savvy, require little to no training
- Advanced in MATLAB, C, Python, Html, CSS, JavaScript

INTERESTS

I enjoy improving my programming skills in my leisure time by doing projects like the portfolio website. I love learning and working on automobiles to gain additional practical knowledge. In the future I would like the improve my welding and machining skill.

REFERENCES

University of Auckland- Senior Lecturer in the Department of Mechanical Engineering Minas Liarokapis - minas.liarokapis@auckland.ac.nz

University of Auckland- Director of Engineering Design Mechanical Engineering Mark Jeunnette - mark.jeunnette@auckland.ac.nz

Rinnai NZ – Heating equipment supplier John Swarbrick – 021 938 363